<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publications on Lok Raj Joshi</title>
    <link>/publication/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publications on Lok Raj Joshi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/publication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A Novel Live Attenuated Vaccine Candidate Protects Against Heterologous Senecavirus A Challenge</title>
      <link>/publication/sva_vaccine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/sva_vaccine/</guid>
      <description>Abstract
Senecavirus A (SVA) is an emerging picornavirus causing vesicular disease (VD) clinically indistinguishable from foot-and-mouth disease (FMD) in pigs. Currently there are no vaccines currently available for SVA. Here we developed a recombinant SVA strain (rSVAm SacII) using reverse genetics and assessed its immunogenicity and protective efficacy in pigs. In vivo characterization of the rSVAm SacII strain demonstrated that the virus is attenuated, as evidenced by absence of lesions, decreased viremia and virus shedding in inoculated animals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deletion of the thymidine kinase gene attenuates Caprine alphaherpesvirus 1 in goats</title>
      <link>/publication/caprine_tk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/caprine_tk/</guid>
      <description>Highlights
•Deletion of the tk gene from the CpHV-1 genome attenuates the virus in goats.
•Traditional infection/transfection resulted in efficient CpHV-1 recombination.
•Both parental and tk-deleted viruses established latency in neurons of the trigeminal ganglia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identification and genetic characterization of a porcine hepe-astrovirus (bastrovirus) in the United States</title>
      <link>/publication/bastrovirus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/bastrovirus/</guid>
      <description>Abstract
Here we describe the identification and genetic characterization of a porcine hepe-astrovirus, or bastrovirus, obtained from feces from pigs in the United States. The genome of the new bastrovirus is 5,955 nt long and contains two open reading frames (ORFs). ORF1 encodes a protein containing three domains, viral methyltransferase, RNA helicase and RNA-dependent RNA polymerase (RdRp), and is closely related to the RdRp of hepatitis E virus. The ORF2 protein shares similarities with the astrovirus capsid precursor protein.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Persistent Infection and Transmission of Senecavirus A from Carrier Sows to Contact Piglets</title>
      <link>/publication/sva_persistence/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/sva_persistence/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Senecavirus A (SVA) is a picornavirus that causes acute vesicular disease (VD), that is clinically indistinguishable from foot-and-mouth disease (FMD), in pigs. Notably, SVA RNA has been detected in lymphoid tissues of infected animals several weeks following resolution of the clinical disease, suggesting that the virus may persist in select host tissues. Here, we investigated the occurrence of persistent SVA infection and the contribution of stressors (transportation, immunosuppression, or parturition) to acute disease and recrudescence from persistent SVA infection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Senecavirus A 3C Protease Mediates Host Cell Apoptosis Late in Infection</title>
      <link>/publication/sva_3c/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/sva_3c/</guid>
      <description>Abstract
Senecavirus A (SVA), an oncolytic picornavirus used for cancer treatment in humans, has recently emerged as a vesicular disease (VD)-causing agent in swine worldwide. Notably, SVA-induced VD is indistinguishable from foot-and-mouth disease (FMD) and other high-consequence VDs of pigs. Here we investigated the role of apoptosis on infection and replication of SVA. Given the critical role of the nuclear factor-kappa B (NF-κB) signaling pathway on modulation of cell death, we first assessed activation of NF-κB during SVA infection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detection of Fowlpox virus carrying distinct genome segments of Reticuloendotheliosis virus</title>
      <link>/publication/fowlpox/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/fowlpox/</guid>
      <description>Abstract
Highlights
•Two distinct FWPV populations were detected in the skin of a wild bird affected with FWPV.
•Metagenomics revealed two FWPV genome populations containing the insertion of REV LTR or the full-length provirus.
•Detection of these distinct populations in other clinical samples of viral isolates suggest that this is a usual event.
•Passage of the FWPV-REV in cell culture resulted in loss of the full-length REV provirus, suggesting instability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pathogenicity and cross-reactive immune responses of a historical and a contemporary Senecavirus A strains in pigs</title>
      <link>/publication/sva-cross-reactive/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/sva-cross-reactive/</guid>
      <description>Abstract
The goals of this study were to compare the pathogenicity and infection dynamics of a historical and a contemporary SVA strains (SVV 001 and SD15-26) and to assess cross-neutralizing and cross-reactive T cell responses following experimental infection in pigs. Both SVA strains successfully infected all inoculated animals, resulting in viremia and robust antibody and cellular immune responses. SVA SD15-26 infection resulted in characteristic clinical signs and vesicular lesions, however, SVA SVV 001 did not cause overt clinical disease with inoculated animals remaining clinically normal during the experiment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Passive immunity to porcine epidemic diarrhea virus following immunization of pregnant gilts with a recombinant orf virus vector expressing the spike protein</title>
      <link>/publication/pedv-passive-immunity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/pedv-passive-immunity/</guid>
      <description>Abstract
Passive immunity is critical for protection of neonatal piglets against porcine epidemic diarrhea virus (PEDV). Here, we investigated the immunogenicity of an orf virus (ORFV) vector expressing the full-length spike (S) protein of PEDV (ORFV-PEDV-S) in pregnant gilts and its ability to confer passive immunity and protection in piglets. Three doses of ORFV-PEDV-S were given to two groups of PEDV-negative pregnant gilts, with the last dose being administered two weeks prior to farrowing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adaptive immune responses following Senecavirus A infection in pigs</title>
      <link>/publication/sva-adaptive/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/sva-adaptive/</guid>
      <description>Abstract
Senecavirus A (SVA), an emerging picornavirus of swine, causes vesicular disease (VD) that is clinically indistinguishable from foot-and-mouth disease (FMD) in pigs. Many aspects of SVA interactions with the host and the host immune responses to infection, however, remain unknown. In the present study, humoral and cellular immune responses to SVA were evaluated following infection in pigs. We show that SVA infection elicited an early and robust virus-neutralizing (VN) antibody response, which coincided and was strongly correlated with VP2- and VP3-specific IgM responses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Immunogenicity of ORFV-based vectors expressing the rabies virus glycoprotein in livestock species</title>
      <link>/publication/orfv-rabies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/orfv-rabies/</guid>
      <description>Abstract
The parapoxvirus Orf virus (ORFV) encodes several immunomodulatory proteins (IMPs) that modulate host-innate and pro-inflammatory responses and has been proposed as a vaccine delivery vector for use in animal species. Here we describe the construction and characterization of two recombinant ORFV vectors expressing the rabies virus (RABV) glycoprotein (G). The RABV-G gene was inserted in the ORFV024 or ORFV121 gene loci, which encode for IMPs that are unique to parapoxviruses and inhibit activation of the NF-κB signaling pathway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A novel bovine papillomavirus type in the genus Dyokappapapillomavirus</title>
      <link>/publication/papilloma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/papilloma/</guid>
      <description>Abstract
Papillomaviruses are a diverse group of viruses that are known to infect a wide range of animal species. Bovine papillomaviruses (BPVs) are divided into at least 21 genotypes (BPV1 to BPV21), with most BPV isolates/strains described to date belonging to one of four genera, including Deltapapillomavirus, Xipapillomavirus, Epsilonpapillomavirus and Dyoxipapillomavirus. Here, we describe the identification and genetic characterization of a new BPV type in the genus Dyokappapapillomavirus. A farm in the state of New York, USA, reported chronic cases of vulvovaginitis in Holstein cows in 2016.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The S2 glycoprotein subunit of porcine epidemic diarrhea virus contains immunodominant neutralizing epitopes</title>
      <link>/publication/pedv-s2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/pedv-s2/</guid>
      <description>Abstract
The porcine epidemic diarrhea virus (PEDV) spike (S) protein is the major target of neutralizing antibodies against PEDV. Here immunodominant neutralizing epitopes of PEDV were identified using a panel of S-specific monoclonal antibodies (mAbs). Ten of eleven S-specific mAbs successfully neutralized PEDV infectivity in vitro. Notably, epitope mapping by peptide ELISAs revealed that nine of these mAbs recognized linear neutralizing epitopes located in the N-terminus of the S2 glycoprotein subunit (amino acids [aa] 744–759, 747–774 and/or 756–771).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genetic characterization and phylogenetic analysis of senecavirus A circulating in the US and in Brazil.</title>
      <link>/publication/sva-brazil/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/sva-brazil/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neonatal pig mortality associated with senecavirus A.</title>
      <link>/publication/sva-embraba/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/sva-embraba/</guid>
      <description>Abstract
Senecavirus A (SVA) is an emerging picornavirus that has been associated with outbreaks of vesicular disease in swine. In 2015, neonatal mortality affecting piglets of 07 days of age correlated with SVA, was reported in Brazil. Here, we present an investigation carried on during 20152016 in five farrowtofinish swine operations in Southern Brazil showing an increased neonatal mortality and also vesicular disease that have been associated to SVA infection. Piglets were lethargic and had a watery diarrhea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pathogenesis of Senecavirus A in finishing pigs</title>
      <link>/publication/sva-pathogenesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/sva-pathogenesis/</guid>
      <description>Abstract
Senecavirus A (SVA) is an emerging picornavirus that has been associated with vesicular disease and neonatal mortality in swine. Many aspects of SVA infection biology and pathogenesis, however, remain unknown. Here the pathogenesis of SVA was investigated in finishing pigs. Animals were inoculated via the oronasal route with SVA strain SD15-26 and monitored for clinical signs and lesions associated with SVA infection. Viraemia was assessed in serum and virus shedding monitored in oral and nasal secretions and faeces by real-time reverse transcriptase quantitative PCR (RT-qPCR) and/or virus isolation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Immunogenicity of a Recombinant Parapoxvirus Expressing the Spike Protein of Porcine Epidemic Diarrhea Virus.</title>
      <link>/publication/orfv-pedv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/orfv-pedv/</guid>
      <description>Abstract
The parapoxvirus Orf virus (ORFV), has long been recognized for its immunomodulatory properties in permissive and non-permissive animal species. Here, a new recombinant ORFV expressing the full-length spike (S) protein of Porcine epidemic diarrhea virus (PEDV) was generated and its immunogenicity and protective efficacy were evaluated in pigs. The PEDV S was inserted into the ORFV121 gene locus, an immunomodulatory gene that inhibits activation of the NF-κB signalling pathway and contributes to ORFV virulence in the natural host.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detection of the emerging picornavirus Senecavirus A in pigs, mice, and houseflies</title>
      <link>/publication/sva-genomic/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/sva-genomic/</guid>
      <description>Abstract
Senecavirus A (SVA) is an emerging picornavirus that has been recently associated with an increased number of outbreaks of vesicular disease and neonatal mortality in swine. Many aspects of SVA infection biology and epidemiology remain unknown. Here, we present a diagnostic investigation conducted in swine herds affected by vesicular disease and increased neonatal mortality. Clinical and environmental samples were collected from affected and unaffected herds and were screened for the presence of SVA by real-time reverse transcriptase PCR and virus isolation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Senecavirus A: A Newly Emerging Picornavirus of Swine</title>
      <link>/publication/sva-editorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/sva-editorial/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prevalence of Vancomycin Resistant Enterococci Species in Minced Buffalo Meat of Chitwan, Nepal</title>
      <link>/publication/vrsa/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/vrsa/</guid>
      <description>Abstract
Methicillin-resistant Staphylococcus aureus (MRSA) has emerged as a significant public health problem both in human and veterinary medicine. Strains of S. aureus resistant to β-lactam antibiotics are known as Methicillin-resistant Staphylococcus aureus (MRSA). Overuse of antibiotics has been ascribed for MRSA emergence. MRSA in cattle was first reported in 1975. Since then, many literatures describing MRSA in cattle have been published. MRSA causes incurable intra-mammary infection and skin diseases in cattle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prevalence of methicillin-resistant Staphylococcus aureus (MRSA) in dairy farms of Pokhara, Nepal.</title>
      <link>/publication/mrsa-milk/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/mrsa-milk/</guid>
      <description>Abstract
MRSA (Methicillin-resistant Staphylococcus aureus) are the strains of S. aureus that are resistant to all the β-lactam antibiotics. MRSA has received a lot of attention in recent years as a zoonotic organism when studies suggested the possibility of animals serving as reservoirs for human MRSA infection. A cross-sectional study was carried out from October, 2012 to January, 2013 to determine the prevalence of MRSA in dairy farms of Pokhara. Milk samples were collected from 10 dairy farms of Pokhara selecting 10 cattle from each farm thereby making a sample size of 100 cattle (400 quarters).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Methicillin-Resistant Staphylococcus Aureus (MRSA) in Cattle: Epidemiology and Zoonotic Implications</title>
      <link>/publication/mrsa-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/mrsa-review/</guid>
      <description>Abstract
Methicillin-resistant Staphylococcus aureus (MRSA) has emerged as a significant public health problem both in human and veterinary medicine. Strains of S. aureus resistant to β-lactam antibiotics are known as Methicillin-resistant Staphylococcus aureus (MRSA). Overuse of antibiotics has been ascribed for MRSA emergence. MRSA in cattle was first reported in 1975. Since then, many literatures describing MRSA in cattle have been published. MRSA causes incurable intra-mammary infection and skin diseases in cattle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Study on the prevalence of Cryptosporidium in calves and HIV infected humans in the periphery of river basins of Kathmandu valley</title>
      <link>/publication/crypto/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/crypto/</guid>
      <description>Abstract
Introduction: Cryptosporidium is an important zoonotic pathogen transmitted primarily through water. This study was conducted to determine the occurrence of Cryptosporidium in calves and humans in relation to the river water in the river basins of Kathmandu.
Materials and Methods: This cross sectional study was conducted from Sept 2012 to Feb 2013. A total of 100 fecal samples (50 calves and 50 HIV/AIDS patients living near the river basins of Kathmandu) were examined for the presence of Cryptosporidium by Ziehl-Neelsen Staining technique after Modified Sheather concentration method with centrifugation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>